PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Although RGB triples
- 虽然 RGB 三数组
are great for representing how we can generate colors,
能很好地表示我们是如何生成颜色的
they aren't natural for artists to use.
但这并不方便艺术家使用
Instead, we use the concept of hue, saturation and lightness
与之不同 我们使用色相、饱和度和透明度的概念
to find the exact color we need.
来找出我们想要的颜色
On the hue saturation wheel,
在色相-饱和度色轮上
the angle around the circle defines the hue,
绕圆形的角度定义了色相
and the radius defines the saturation.
半径定义了饱和度
The position in this circle is then combined
圆形中的位置和
with the setting of the Lightness slider
亮度滑动条
to define a final color.
一同定义了最终的颜色
From now on I'm gonna call this Lightness slider
从现在起我将称呼亮度滑动条为
the Lightness Dimension,
亮度维度
since it only requires a single number to define,
因为它仅需要一个数字就可以定义
and this color, which is defined using these HSL settings,
于是 这个用 HSL 集合定义的颜色
is also some position in the RGB color cube.
也会落在 RGB 色彩立方体中
That brings us to a key problem in this lesson.
这给我们带来了本堂课的一个关键问题
How does each HSL setting
每个 HSL 集合是如何
convert into a unique point in the RGB cube?
转变为 RGB 色彩立方体中特定的点的
First, let's think about how we can go from a 3D cube
首先 我们先想想我们如何从 3D 的立方体
to a 2D circle.
变成一个 2D 的圆形
The trick is to think about where the grays are
诀窍就是想想灰色
in our color cube.
在色彩立方体的什么地方
Anywhere in our color cube where the RGB values are equal,
在色彩立方体中 任何 RGB 值相等的地方
we get some shade of gray.
我们都会得到某种灰色
For example, 20%, 20%, 20%, gives us this darker gray,
举个例子 (20%,20%,20%) 给了我们一个暗灰色
and 80%, 80%, 80%, gives us this lighter gray.
而 (80%,80%,80%) 给了我们一个亮灰色
That means there's a line of gray within our RGB cube,
这表示我们的 RBG 立方体中有一条表示灰色的线
meaning that there's only one dimension needed
也就是说仅用一个维度即可
to describe all grays.
描述所有的灰色
So let's rotate the color cube
所以让我们旋转这个色彩立方体
so that we're looking directly down at the gray line.
这样我们就可以沿着灰线直直地看下去
Does it look familiar?
看来很熟悉不是么？
Mathematicians cheat a bit and deform this into a circle.
数学家们耍了些手段把它变成了圆形
There's some fancy math to make this stretching happen,
有些很神奇的数学让这个拉伸变为可能
but we'll ignore it here.
不过我们在此先不管它
And that's where the hue saturation wheel comes from.
这就是色相-饱和度色轮的来历
Finally, we can get to the Lightness Dimension.
最后我们就来到了亮度维度
To do this, we pop back into 3D space
为了定义它 我们将我们的圆形拉高
by growing our circle into a cylinder.
以回到 3D 空间
The Lightness Dimension defines what slice
亮度维度定义了我们将从
we take out of our color cylinder.
色彩圆柱中拿出哪片来
A Lightness value of 50% takes a slice out of the middle,
亮度值为 50% 将从正中央抽出一片来
and to lighten the shade of any color on this wheel,
而为了增亮这片色轮中的任何颜色
we're moving up the Lightness Dimension to a higher slice,
我们将亮度维度向上移动至一个更高的圆片上
and to darken the color,
而减暗颜色
we move down the Lightness Dimension to a lower slice.
我们将亮度维度向下移动至一个更低的圆片上
Okay, this is important, so let's pause here.
好啦 这很重要 我们先在这里暂停
In the next exercise,
在下一个练习中
we'll challenge you to think about this model a little more.
我们会挑战你一下 让你多想一想这个模型
Take your time and have fun. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
放慢脚步好好玩 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox